<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on</title><link>/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Editing Project Instructions</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-4/editing-project-instructions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-4/editing-project-instructions/</guid><description>Part 1:
Take your recordings from the studio and edit them in your DAW. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t made your recordings yet find some from freesound to do the activity. Remove unwanted material from the beginning and ending of the recording. Cut sounds into separate files and name them appropriately. Apply fades to the start and end to avoid clicks. Raise the levels of the recordings so they are all similar. Export each file separately and submit to d2l.</description></item><item><title>MIDI editing</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-8/midi-editing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-8/midi-editing/</guid><description>Recording with a MIDI keyboard Click track Computer keyboard as MIDI keyboard octave up and down, velocity up and down Pencil enter MIDI Draw in multiple notes with the pencil tool - b Insert MIDI clip Preview switch to audition sounds as you enter them Change grid setting Fixed grid and triplet grid narrow grid - cmd + 1 widen grid - cmd + 2 triplet grid - cmd + 3 toggle grid on off - cmd + 4 Step record Click note on keyboard then hold down arrow key, click and release to determine the length of the note Editing MIDI Quantize Quantize settings Quantize to the smallest rhythmic increment in your clip Groove quantization - .</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/pages/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/projects/</guid><description>Project 1 - Starting the sample pack. Work in groups of 2-4 in the recording studio. One person “performs” while the other tracks, and anyone left over watches how to track. Pick one thing to record, an instrument or an object.
Make at least 10 recordings. These will be used to build your own personal sample pack. Decide if you want these to be &amp;ldquo;musical&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;sound effects&amp;rdquo; recordings. If you decide to record something more musical, be sure to note the tempo and key of whatever you record, so that you can compose something more easily in the editing process.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/pages/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/resources/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>/pages/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/schedule/</guid><description>table { border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; } tr { border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; } th { text-align: left; } } Week Date Topics, Assignments, Quizzes, Tests, Deadlines 1 8/24, 8/26 Tuesday 8/24:
Me - Dr. Carson Class introductions Name? Class year? Where are you from? What&amp;rsquo;s your favorite game or movie? Syllabus Perusall signup I will assign readings, videos, or podcasts through Perusall.</description></item><item><title>Syllabus</title><link>/pages/syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/syllabus/</guid><description>Course Prefix, Number, and Title: DAD 222 – Audio Production I: Foundations
Credits: 3
University Name: Dakota State University
Academic Term/Year: Fall 2021
Last date to Drop and receive 100% refund: September 2nd, 2021
Last date to Withdraw and earn a grade of &amp;lsquo;W&amp;rsquo;: November 5th, 2021
Course Meeting Time and Location: Tuesday / Thursday 9:30 am – 10:45 am TCB 209
Instructor Information: Name: Tate Carson Office: TCB 305 Email Address: Tate.</description></item></channel></rss>